<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AeonNeo</title>
    <description>A myriad of thoughts</description>
    <link>https://www.yangvincent.com</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.yangvincent.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Effective Altruism</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;prioritization of how we can maximize impact to help current + future humans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/80000-hours/&quot;&gt;80000 Hours&lt;/a&gt; has some surprising research and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guidedtrack.com/programs/3025/embed/auth?source=https%3A%2F%2F80000hours.org%2Fproblem-quiz%2F&quot;&gt;quiz &lt;/a&gt; here. It turns out that my current work in [[security]] is likely maximally impactful, since it allows me to help protect the development of &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/ai/&quot;&gt;ai&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://80000hours.org/problem-profiles/&quot;&gt;problem profiles&lt;/a&gt;, which takes many problems and ranks them.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;helping create safe AI
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;global priorities research&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;working against global warming was surprisingly really far down the list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/effective-altruism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/effective-altruism/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ai</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is for general notes on AI&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/ai/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/ai/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>80000 Hours</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a website created to help you figure out how to have the most impact with your time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/80000-hours/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/80000-hours/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Github hates Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve spent a lot of time thinking about how I want to manage my data and my notes. I’ve previously 
used Roam Research and Notion, but I’m scared that those might someday force me to pay or worse, lose my data.
I’ve decided to instead create a clone of the features I enjoy here so I can just put all my notes online and
access them whenever. The downside is that I can’t modify them on mobile, but I’m okay with that loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search with Algolia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travis CI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimated reading time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bidirectional Linking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;algolia&quot;&gt;Algolia&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrating with Algolia was absurdly simple. You add a few snippets of code and send your pages over to them so they can build a search index. They even help you set up Travis CI so this index gets rebuilt whenever you push new changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;travis-ci&quot;&gt;Travis CI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got this for free with Algolia, but it’s a little bit sad doing dependency management here. Specifically, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle&lt;/code&gt; doesn’t play well with newer versions of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;json&lt;/code&gt; so in its infinite wisdom, Travis CI (but really the problem is Ruby) decides to die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bidirectional-linking&quot;&gt;Bidirectional linking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created this by looking over and over at how Generators work in Jekyll. It was a ton of googling how to do very basic things in Ruby and slowly hacking it together. Some learnings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generators work by taking in some information and outputting other information that can be read by each page to become content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have to first look through all posts to find where all the links are pointing to, then reverse this so we can see where all the links are pointing from.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I should probably change my plugin to an actual Gem, but I’m lazy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Github doesn’t allow us to install plugins because they mandate safe mode!!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I found a reasonable tool to use Github to host, but disable their Jekyll (jgd – jekyll github deploy). It works by taking a source branch, building it, and dumping it on a resulting branch to build.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Github forces you to use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; to build on a name branch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github hates Jekyll. You heard it here first.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/github-hates-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/github-hates-jekyll/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fried Rice</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.averiecooks.com/easy-better-takeout-chicken-fried-rice/&quot;&gt;Recipe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/fried-rice/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/fried-rice/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dumplings</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.averiecooks.com/easy-better-takeout-chicken-fried-rice/&quot;&gt;Recipe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/dumplings/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/dumplings/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cooking</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/fried-rice/&quot;&gt;Fried Rice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/dumplings/&quot;&gt;Dumplings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/80000-hours/&quot;&gt;Asked&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/cooking/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/cooking/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roam Research</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Roam Research recently moved to a paid model. Not that I don’t support their product, it’s quite good, but it’s pushing
me to realize that I can’t rely on other products to always behave the same or have my best interests at heart. They did,
however, bring up a really good idea – that our thoughts are inherently graph-structured and keeping our notes in a similar fashion makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memex provides a reasonable alternative: it allows me to take notes and annotations on webpages I read as well as full-text search through them.
However, this doesn’t have the “web” built in. Rather, it relies on normal search. I want to continue writing notes
with this graph based structure but with something that has a mobile app &amp;amp; looks a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A realistic alternative might actually to just take a bunch of notes in Markdown, then create a function that
automatically ingests tags in Jekyll and transforms them into links to appropriate pages. In this way, we could also detect and create 
bidirectional links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already have markdown &amp;amp; latex support, so this would probably only take a day to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime though, looks like I might have to use Notion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/roam-research/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/roam-research/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>weblog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know blog is short for weblog?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of this page (and the blog category) are inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aaronsw.com/weblog/&quot;&gt;Aaron Swartz&lt;/a&gt;. It’s
intended as a space for me to put miscellaneous thoughts into the void but not quite so far that I can’t retrieve it on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More organized thoughts, guides, and links go in Resources, and explicitly written-for-public-consumption reads are under /stories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/weblog/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/weblog/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Heavenly</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some complaints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heavenly isn’t very friendly to snowboarders. There are tons of flats. From California to Nevada (Skyline Trail), Round a bout, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect resorts to have internet connection or reliable wifi at lodges. They’re often a central place to meet up, and not having internet makes this loads more difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nobody wants to end the day waiting for a gondola to bring them down, but Heavenly doesn’t have any runs from East Peak Lodge to Boulder Lodge. At California Lodge, there are no beginner friendly routes down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There aren’t many beginner friendly runs. The runs that are are also spread apart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, there are some nice aspects as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s close to Nevada, so gambling is allowed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They have powder house nearby, which has incredibly cheap rentals and great employees.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They have one of the best views and challenging (imo)  double blacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/heavenly/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/heavenly/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Family</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s nice that my family has grown closer as Kevin and I have grown up. In
all honesty our relationship was incredibly strained early on as my parents pressured me to
pick up “regular hobbies” like Kevin’s, practice more violin, and do better in school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up making a large deal with them which ended with my gaining significant independence.
Ever since, my parents and my relationship has significantly improved, as we now interact as equals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.yangvincent.com/assets/images/family/mom_dad.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Parents&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have incredible variation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father enjoys classical music, nature, and reading. He’s also 
fully content on his own. Growing up, all of our family vacations were nature-based thanks to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mother on the other hand is extremely social. She cares deeply about tai chi and eastern
medicine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin is your “true adventurer” who enjoys solo travel, beautiful views, and photography. 
Currently, he cares about sustainable architecture. You can easily see the similarities to my dad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a reasonable mix of both. I enjoy CS along with my dad, and we’re both interested in optimizing
our lives – how can you find your purpose and maximize it? How can you spent your time efficiently? 
I also enjoy nature, though I’m far more interested in cities. In other ways however,
I’m far more similar to my mom. She’s extremely social, as am I. She’s also fairly stubborn and argumentative, as am I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;kevin-dad&quot; src=&quot;https://www.yangvincent.com/assets/images/family/kevin_dad.jpg&quot; data-rotate=&quot;90&quot; alt=&quot;kevin and dad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/family/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/family/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vacation to Australia!</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently traveled to Australia for my annual trip with my friends from SD. Specifically, this trip was with
Josh, Divya, and Alan. We visited 3 locations (each of which in its own biome!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-brief-history&quot;&gt;A Brief History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Australia has quite an interesting history. Several hundred years ago, the UK decided that they had too
many convicts so they dumped all of their criminals into Australia. Today, Australia has a lower crime rate.
They also had several racist laws until fairly recently, trying to keep the nation white. I actually
somewhat felt the effect of this, as the only people who went out of their way to help us were asian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sydney&quot;&gt;Sydney&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sydney was a pretty nice, bustling city. There’s some spectacular downtown spots that highly consisted of thai,
sushi, and bars. We also met a girl on the flight who talked about some of her study abroad experiences at the
University of Sydney. On the first night while wandering around and looking for night life, we stumbled
upon a private concert by Flume celebrating the opening of the new Louis Vuitton store!
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.yangvincent.com/assets/images/australia/flume.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flume's private concert for LV&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cairns&quot;&gt;Cairns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cairns was beautiful as well. Driving along the coast felt like living a music video. The great barrier reef is
definitely not doing well, but it was my first time seeing so much biodiversity. At one point,
I even saw a shark while scuba diving! Scuba is really interesting because being so far under water actually
feels quite foreign, especially with all of the equipment involved. We had to go through training
to learn how to get water out of goggles and how to get the respirator back in after it got waterlogged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cairns also had Hartley’s Crocodile Park, which was absolutely mind blowing. Crocs can survive for up to a year
on a single chicken, and they show feedings literally feets away from where you are. Crocs have an insanely
high bite force, so hearing the jaws clamp is awe inspiring. Hartley’s also acts as a sanctuary because they
collect the eggs in order to supply the croc industry. They also had a really fun nocturnal exhibit where we saw
kangaroo mice and tons of other weird rodents!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;uluru&quot;&gt;Uluru&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, we spent a little too much time in Uluru. It was around 105 degrees every day, so we spent a ton of time
in our jail cell-like room doing random shenanigans. Riding camels was quite fun, and digideroos are incredibly difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/australia/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/australia/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hang Gliding</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently started looking into hanggliding. It’s more appealing to me than paragliding cause there’s fewer parts (and probably easier setup).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s several gyms near me: East Bay, Pacifica, Mission Peak, Milpitas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The death rate is around 1 death per 1,000 active pilots per year. A full set of gear costs around 4k. People can get in the air and go straight after
the first lesson. There are several levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In progress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/hanggliding/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/hanggliding/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Companies</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m lucky to work on a topic I’m passionate about with intelligent people willing to mentor me at a company that treats me well. This situation has pushed me
to have strong opinions about how companies should operate and what employees should be free to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;optics&quot;&gt;Optics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optics are when people explicitly stay longer or come in earlier to demonstrate to others that they’re working an adequate amount. This makes no sense. The 
amount of time spent at work has minimal relation to the actual amount of work being done, and the ‘day to day impressions’ of random people on your floor
should be minimally impactful (read: not AT ALL) on your performance rating, which should be the sole determinant of promotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other easy examples are artificially increasing the number of relevant team members to make a task seem bigger than it is. Represent your work accurately, 
and difficult/valuable work will be naturally rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;transparency&quot;&gt;Transparency&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be clear and coherent about your preferences. Give helful feedback when necessary and be open to receiving feedback in turn. Seek to listen then explain, so
everyone can understand others’ points of view. Only by understanding the other pov can you successfully negotiate and/or engage their sympathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might not be as drastic as the Bridgewater dot system, but in all honesty I support that as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;management&quot;&gt;Management&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies shouldn’t allow current managers to block their subordinates’ movements. Transfers should be solely dependent on the consent of the new team and the moving 
employee in question. This prevents employees from being fucked over by their managers and prevents people from working in toxic environments. Even if this
may leave a team short-handed, any sufficiently important team should have capable management and adequate resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People should feel comfortable talking to their managers and vice versa. They should be on the same “team” against the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My old manager told me this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My priorities are as follows. You, the team, the org, the company, the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that if something is advantageous only to me and not the team, he’ll still support it. If there’s an alternative that’s equally
advantageous to me but also benefits the team, then he’ll push for that, and so on/so forth. This is fantastic because it allows me to trust
that the manager will always want what’s best for me, regardless of how it may impact the team. LinkedIn also has this ingrained in their 
core culture. “I know that you won’t always be here, but I’ll help you get where you want and you give me good work in the meantime”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;performance-reviews&quot;&gt;Performance Reviews&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People’s performance reviews should be dependent on an objective view of their work. Unfortuantely, work is often difficult to quantify, but we can get a reasonable understanding by asking coworkers and subject matter experts. These (and hard metrics from an employee’s projects) should be the only determinants for a promotion. Promotions shouldn’t have to be “fought for” by a manager;
the work should speak for itself and be able to be represented by anyone equally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;salary&quot;&gt;Salary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salary data should be public. Companies buy massive datasets of what other companies pay, and can select by region, field, role, growth stage, etc. This works against the employees. Employees should
know how much they’re worth and how much more/less they could be making, as opposed to being forced to interview to re-negotiate for a higher salary each time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject-matter&quot;&gt;Subject Matter&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find an area where you’re curious or passionate about. This allows you to worry more about how to solve the problems. Provided sufficient mentorship/intelligence/time, 
solid results should follow regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/companies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/companies/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Societal Structure</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently had several extensive discussions about what kind of society we live in and what society we would
want to live in. Several definitions are important and useful for future topics/conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;definitions&quot;&gt;Definitions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Socialism: Abolishes classes, significant ‘welfare’ programs, People are taxed based on ability, and given aid based on
their contributions. Private ownership.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communism: Abolishes classes, no private ownership, people are taxed on ability, and given need-based aid.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Democracy: People elect those in power (opposite: fascism)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fascism: Dictatorship&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capitalism: Private ownership, market sets prices/demand/etc. Classes exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/societal-structure/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/societal-structure/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rafting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This last weekend I want rafting with a bunch of colleagues. One employee went out of her way to plan out a 3-day trip
for 100 people! Rafting consisted of the lower south fork and middle fork of the American river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, I’d only tried up to class 3 before, but the rapids for class 4 were a whole new ball game. The guides for
this round were also significantly better than any others I’ve had. We surfed, did tricks with spinning off rocks and shifting
the boat’s weight to one side, swam in the middle of eddies to spin, and many other fun rafting nuances I’d never
heard of before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between each class of rapids is as follows. Class 1: no work required. Class 2: Mild rapids, no real work 
required. Class 3: Some rapids, maneuvering helpful. Class 4. Accuracy within several feet to navigate rapids. Class 5: 
Accuracy within inches to navigate rapids. Class 6: Literally will die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rapids are graded on the easiest route through them, but may have multiple ratings for specific lines taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall definitely a fantastic experience. Met some interesting people, had a phenomenal time rafting and learning about the
guides’ lives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/rafting/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/rafting/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Life Workflow</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose we want to hone ourselves to be as productive as possible. This might look like training for a competition or
creating a startup or learning/growing in any other capacity, but acting efficiently is always in our best interest. How
might we do so? What base components should we have in our life to allow us to excel elsewhere? These are the things
I’ve found thus far. Keep in mind that maximizing efficiency is a means, not an end. The end is maximizing fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;health&quot;&gt;Health&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get enough sleep every day. If you don’t, repay this debt as soon as you can. Exercise as much as you can; it chemically
makes you happier as a side benefit. Drink tons of water. Sleep early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mental-health&quot;&gt;Mental Health&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure out what affects your mood. Mine is highly dependent on how optimistic I feel for the future and how
secure I feel with my friends. Surround yourself with good people who will pick you up and push you to achieve more.
Talk about your problems with others and listen to theirs in turn. Care about people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-a-todo-list-and-a-calendar&quot;&gt;Keep a TODO list and a calendar&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our brains are disappointingly incapable of keeping track of tabs/monitoring. We’re far better at working through
well-defined problems. Luckily, we can offset these operations to tools. I keep a running list of “Things to do today”
and “Things to do later”. Before each task, consider – why am I doing this? What happens if I don’t?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Any time anything crosses your life, you’ve got to ask: This thing I’m thinking about doing – why am I doing it?
What will happen if I don’t? The best thing is when I have something on my todo list and I think “hmm, no”.
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oTugjssqOT0&quot;&gt;Randy Pausch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m lucky enough to not procrastinate much, but only because having notifications on my reminders app (Todoist) frustrates
me to no end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-feedback&quot;&gt;Get feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback is crucial for calibrating your expectations. Find out what the people around you think about the way you do things,
how they do things and instead, then consider if you’d like to incorporate them for yourself as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/life-workflow/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/life-workflow/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Computer Workflow</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I’ve put in many hours to make my processes more efficient. I spend 40 hours a week, if not more
at a computer; it makes sense to streamline this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related posts are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yangvincent.com/dev-workflow/&quot;&gt;Development Workflow&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yangvincent.com/life-workflow/&quot;&gt;Life Workflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’d like to cover several tools, how they work, and how they work together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kinesis Advantage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keyboard Layouts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple screens&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vimium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hardware&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://kinesis-ergo.com/shop/advantage2/&quot;&gt;Kinesis Advantage&lt;/a&gt; is a marvel of a keyboard. It’s composed of
two large wells placed horizontally; one for each hand. The wells’ distance from each other allows me to keep my
arms shoulder-width apart which minimizes ulnar deviation. &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.yangvincent.com/assets/images/comp-workflow/wrist.png&quot; alt=&quot;ulnar deviation&quot; /&gt;
Also, the wells allow me to maintain natural wrist curvature where my palm is supported and neither my wrist nor
my fingers support more weight than they should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has cherry brown switches which are quieter than blues and reasonably suited for workplaces. Mechanical
switches are better than rubber keyboards because they last longer provide specific actuation points without
bottoming out. In other words, you don’t need to mash on them to type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it has ortholinear rows (i.e. all of the keys are placed vertically and not offset), which allows my fingers
to naturally move up and down while keeping all keys closer to the home row. Finally, it moves some of the most
important keys to the thumb (backspace, control, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keyboard-layouts&quot;&gt;Keyboard Layouts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I interchange between Dvorak and Qwerty. Dvorak was created to minimize finger movement in several ways. Vowels are placed on 
the left and keys are generally placed to maximize hand alternation. The most popular keys are on the home row,
with the subsequent keys placed on the top, and finally the least used keys on bottom. Unfortunately, I’ve never reached
the same speed on Dvorak as I have on Qwerty, so I use it in limited capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;importance-of-screen-size&quot;&gt;Importance of Screen Size&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have 3 monitors at home. I’ve found this is optimal so everything I might want to maintain in my mind and reasonably
access quickly can be done so with ease. This often looks like a screen with 4 panes of code, another monitor for docs,
and finally one more for miscellaneous items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vimium&quot;&gt;Vimium&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m strongly against using the mouse; I believe our arms should never move (or only move minimally) from the keyboard
since everything can be done from the keyboard. Vimium allows me to browse/navigate webpages/search, etc. without
using the mouse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/comp-workflow/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/comp-workflow/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Information Security Symposium</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently spoke at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cvent.com/events/2019-information-security-symposium/custom-35-2bf6e0b8a1fd41a78a7211e81fcd1fd8.aspx?cpc=H7NM3FQB9TN&quot;&gt;Davis Security Symposium&lt;/a&gt; with my friend Harrison Nguyen
about &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20190624185212/https://www.cvent.com/events/2019-information-security-symposium/agenda-2bf6e0b8a1fd41a78a7211e81fcd1fd8.aspx?cpc=H7NM3FQB9TN&quot;&gt;healthcare and blockchain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gist of the paper is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Health information exchange is important and complicated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Despite &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=millions+invested+into+blockchain+healthcare&amp;amp;oq=millions+invested+into+blockchain+healthcare&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j33.4783j1j1&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;millions being invested into blockchain + healthcare solutions&lt;/a&gt;, 
blockchain remains a premature technology.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At its core, blockchain allows us to act without a trusted 3rd party. For healthcare, this means blockchain would manage our permissions for who can access health records (infeasible to actually store the images).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who would run these nodes? The hospital? 3rd parties? Other patients? If so, can we guarantee that at least 50% would be honest? No.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most benefits of blockchain are really just of PKI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I also realized that many people still don’t understand how blockchain works even though there’s many resources talking about how it fundamentally works. It’s difficult to discuss further implications of this
technology with people don’t have a strong understanding of its capabilities yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also quite a significant split between people who are in IT security and research security.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/infosec-symposium/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/infosec-symposium/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Development Workflow</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a strong believer that we should improve both at what we do and how we do it.
I spend hours at a computer telling it what to do; it follows that I should improve
&lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; I tell it what to do. In this post, I’ll focus on plugins/tips/tricks for my development tools.
IMO (and in the opinion of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ux.stackexchange.com/questions/30682/are-there-any-recent-studies-of-the-keyboard-vs-mouse-issue&quot;&gt;these studies&lt;/a&gt;), 
using only the keyboard should be faster than the mouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vim (Emacs + evil mode)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zsh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tmux&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;fzf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vim&quot;&gt;Vim&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim’s philosophy is that you edit text in modes – moving around and editing.
You can find articles on this virtually everywhere, so I’ll focus on what I find more unique: the plugins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;evil&quot;&gt;Evil&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emacs has better “large feature” support. You can run things that hook back in asynchronously
and even run their version of vim, in emacs (evil).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;kythe&quot;&gt;Kythe&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kythe/kythe&quot;&gt;Kythe&lt;/a&gt; is an ecosystem that seeks to “understand” code.
Specifically, it allows tools to communicate across languages. This is helpful in Vim because
it helps you find, for instance, the definition of a function, or where that function
may be called, or the documentation for a function. This allows you to “click through”
in vim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;jumplist&quot;&gt;Jumplist&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;C-i&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;C-o&lt;/code&gt; to jump forward and backward in a jump list. Typically, you’re supposed 
to open multiple buffers for all your files so you don’t completely close vim for hours at a time.
When you jump to/from functions and in/out of various files, this will track where you’ve been and
let you navigate this history easily. Think of it as moving forward and backward in time, vs space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zsh&quot;&gt;Zsh&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nice interactive, powerful shell with pleasant community support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;zsh-command-time&quot;&gt;zsh-command-time&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track and output how long each command took.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tmux&quot;&gt;Tmux&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tmux allows you to group your terminals and split/configure them however you like.
The plugin manager is called tpm. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tmux-plugins&quot;&gt;Here is a huge list of plugins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;tmux-resurrect&quot;&gt;tmux-resurrect&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preserves your contents even when you leave sessions/close down the server completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;tmux-continuum&quot;&gt;tmux-continuum&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allows you to reload buffer contents (even stuff like vim files!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fzf&quot;&gt;fzf&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fzf allows you to fuzzy search through a list of strings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;fasd&quot;&gt;fasd&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fasd sorts past commands by frequency and recency (frecency). When coupled with fzf, it is
a powerful way to fuzzy search through opening files you open often. It basically becomes 
global project or content search that can be coupled with vim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;history&quot;&gt;history&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fzf and history is nice too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/dev-workflow/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yangvincent.com//posts/dev-workflow/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
